Walking with the Enemy is a action, drama,
history film directed by Mark Schmidt.
Regent Horthy is the leader of Hungary and a German ally, but his favorable
standing with Hitler changes as the war comes to an end.
Forced to cede Hungary’s power or else witness the execution of his son, Regent Horthy gives up control of his
country to the Nazis, who quickly move Hungarians to ghettos and death camps, with no hope in sight.
But the despair changes when a young man named Elek emerges.
Separated from his family during the relocations and aided by the woman
he loves , Elek defies the enemy by becoming one of them.
In a race against time, disguised as a Nazi Officer he embarks on a
mission to save his family and thousands of his countrymen.
Elek Cohen, played by Jonas Armstrong.
Hannah Schoen, played by Hannah Tointon.
Regent Miklos Horthy, played by Ben Kingsley.
Miklos Schoen, played by Simon Dutton.
Lt. Colonel Otto Skorzeny, played by Burn Gorman.
Miklos Horthy Jr., played by Shane Taylor.
Walking with the Enemy is a 2014 American action drama film directed by
Mark Schmidt, and scripted by Kenny Golde and Mark Schmidt.
The film stars Jonas Armstrong, Ben Kingsley, Simon Kunz, Hannah
Tointon, Simon Dutton, Burn Gorman, and Charles Hubbell.
It is inspired by the true story of Pinchas Tibor Rosenbaum.
Set in Budapest and nearby villages, it depicts the German occupation of
Hungary during the final months of the Second World War.
The story is about a young Hungarian-Jewish man, Elek Cohen (played by Jonas Armstrong), who dons an SS uniform to
pose as an officer to find out the fate of his family and to rescue fellow Jews from the Holocaust.
The tone is emotional.